ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError.
ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError.
You'll encounter this error if your code\hchanges a value after change detection\hhas been run and the view has been built.\h
如果你的程式碼在執行完變更檢測 並建構好檢視之後又修改了某個值，就會遇到本錯誤
You'll only see this error in development\h because Angular runs an additional change\h\h
你只會在開發模式下看到本錯誤 因為 Angular 會執行一次額外的
detection check to catch errors like\h this that can cause erratic UI behavior.\h
變更檢測來捕獲此類錯誤 此類錯誤會導致古怪的 UI 行為
The extra check ensures the app is stable and that\h all data updates have been reflected in the views.\h
這次額外的檢查可以確保應用已進入穩定態 對資料的所有更新都已經反映到了檢視上
There are a variety of reasons the view might\h be left in an inconsistent state,
有很多原因都可能導致檢視處於不一致狀態
such as code\hthat updates the view during the AfterViewInit\h lifecycle hook or when change detection triggers\h\h
比如某些程式碼在 AfterViewInit 鉤子中更新了檢視 或變更檢測觸發器自身進入了無限迴圈
itself in an infinite loop, like a method that\h returns a different value each time,
比如某個被繫結的方法每次都返回不同的值
or a child\hcomponent that changes the bindings on its parent.
或者某個子元件修改了其父元件/父指令上的繫結
Let's start by looking at a simple reproduction\hand solution.
我們來看一個簡單的問題復現及其解決方案
Then, we'll take a more detailed\h look at Angular's change detection to understand\h\h
然後，我們仔細看一下 Angular 的變更檢測，以便理解
why this error happens and why it's important. Here in the app component template we're using\h\h
為什麼會發生本錯誤，以及它為何如此重要 這裡是我們正在使用的 AppComponent 範本
the ngIf directive with a loading boolean. In the model, or our component type script,\h\h
ngIf 指令帶有一個布林值 loading 在模型（也就是我們的元件 TypeScript 程式碼）中
we give it a default value of true. Then, using\h the AfterViewInit lifecycle hook we flip the\h\h
我們給了它一個預設值 true 然後，在 AfterViewInit 鉤子中
value to false when it's done loading. But when we run this code we see\h\h
當載入完成時，我們把它的值翻轉為 false 但是當我們執行此程式碼時，會看到報錯：
ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError:\h Previous value: false, Current value: true.\h
ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError: Previous value: false, Current value: true.
Now in a more complex app it might not be\h clear where this error originates from,\h\h
在更復雜的應用中，錯誤的源頭可能沒這麼清晰
but you can always assume that it has\h something to do with a binding in the template.\h
但是你始終可以假設，它對範本中的繫結做了點什麼
In the stack trace you'll find a link to the\h source map for the component template that\h\h
在呼叫堆疊追蹤中，你會發現一個連結 它指向導致本錯誤的元件範本的原始碼對映
caused the error and it takes us directly\h to the line of code that caused the issue,\h\h
並且它直接把我們帶到了導致此問題的程式碼行
which is our ngIf binding to the loading boolean. What the error is trying to tell us is that\h\h
也就是我們繫結到 loading 屬性的 ngIf 陳述式 本錯誤在試圖告訴我們
the loading value has changed after the change\h detection cycle has completed, but what exactly\h\h
這個 loading 屬性的值在變更檢測迴圈完成之後發生了變化
is wrong with our code in this case? The short answer is that we're using\h\h
但是在這個例子中我們的程式碼到底錯在哪裡呢？ 簡短的答案是我們正在使用錯誤的
the wrong lifecycle hook. If we move our code from\h\h
生命週期鉤子 如果我們把程式碼從
AfterViewInit to OnInit the error goes\h away and everything works perfectly.\h
AfterViewInit 移到 OnInit 中，本錯誤就消失了 這些就恢復正常了
In other words, if you find yourself updating\h values in AfterViewInit there's a good chance\h\h
換句話說，如果你發現自己正在 AfterViewInit 中修改值
that a simple refactor to OnInit or the\h component constructor will fix the issue.\h
就可以簡單地把它移到 OnInit 或元件建構函式中來修復它
Okay, at this point we know we used the wrong\h lifecycle hook and we can fix it by refactoring,\h\h
現在，我們已經明白使用了錯誤的生命週期鉤子 並且可以透過重構來修復它
but to really understand why let's do a quick\h review of how change detection works in Angular.\h
但要想真正理解其原因，我們就要快速回顧一下 Angular 中變更檢測的工作原理
The goal of change detection is to\h keep the model, your typescript code,\h\h
變更檢測的目標，是讓模型（TypeScript 程式碼）與
in sync with the template, your html. And it does so by looking for data\h\h
範本（HTML）保持同步 它實現這一點的方式，是透過
changes in the component tree from top to bottom. First it checks the parent, then the first child,\h\h
在元件樹中自頂向下查詢資料變更 首先它檢查父元件，然後是子元件
second child and so on, but if we update a\h binding on the parent after it has already\h\h
然後是二級子元件，以此類推。但是如果我們在 父元件完成變更檢查之後再修改某個繫結
been checked Angular will throw the error. Now what we have here is a simplified\h\h
Angular 就會丟擲本錯誤 現在，我們有了一個簡化的
breakdown of Angular's life cycle, or the steps\h it performs when a component is first initialized.\h
Angular 生命週期分解圖
First it updates the bindings like\h the ngIf directive in the template.\h
首先它像此範本中的 ngIf 指令一樣修改這些繫結
Then it runs the OnInit lifecycle\h hook, updates the DOM, then runs\h\h
然後，它執行 OnInit 生命週期鉤子 修改 DOM，然後執行子元件的變更檢測
change detection for the child component. Notice how the final step is AfterViewInit,\h\h
要注意，這裡的最後一步是 AfterViewInit
and more importantly that it\h runs after change detection.\h
更重要的是它執行在變更檢測之後
Basically any code that runs here\h should not attempt to update the view\h\h
基本上，這裡執行的所有程式碼 都不應該嘗試更新其檢視
and that was the root of the problem in this case. Refactoring to OnInit works great for initial\h\h
這就是本例子中問題的根源 把它重構到 OnInit 中對於初始值是非常合適的
values, but if that doesn't fix the issue there\h are a few other ways you may have encountered\h\h
但是如果這沒能修復本錯誤 那可能是因為其它原因導致了本錯誤
this error, along with additional ways to fix it. In the component here, we're using ViewChild to\h\h
那就要用其它方式來修復它 在此元件中，我們正在用 ViewChild 從 DOM 樹中捕獲某個元素
grab an element from the DOM, but this\h element won't be available until the\h\h
但是此元素在呼叫完 AfterViewInit 鉤子之前是不可用的
AfterViewInit lifecycle hook is called. But what if we can't update the state of\h\h
但是我們卻不能在得到此 ViewChild 元素之前
the component until after we\h have the ViewChild element?\h
更新元件的狀態，這下該怎麼辦呢？
If we can't refactor to ngOnInit,\h we have a couple of other options.\h
如果我們不能重構到 ngOnInit 中 我們還有另外一些選擇
An approach you'll often see on StackOverflow\h answers is to make the update asynchronous.\h
你在 StackOverflow 答案中經常看到的方法之一 就是進行非同步更新
When we make the update async, it'll be\h picked up on the next change detection\h\h
當我們進行非同步更新時，它會推到下一次變更檢測週期中進行
check and prevent the error from occurring. We can make it asynchronous by wrapping it in\h\h
這樣就會防止發生錯誤 我們可以把它包裹進一個延遲為 0 的 setTimeout 中
a set timeout with a delay of zero. That'll put\h the update in the next macro task queue of the\h\h
來把它變成非同步的 這樣就會把此更新推到 JavaScript 事件迴圈的下一個宏任務佇列中
Javascript event loop. Alternatively we can use\h a promise that resolves immediately, then run the\h\h
另外，我可以還可以使用一個立即解析的 Promise，然後在其
update in its callback. This code will achieve the\h same result, the only subtle difference is that\h\h
回呼(Callback)中執行此更新。這段程式碼會達到同樣的效果 但是有一些微妙的差異：
it runs on the micro task queue before the end of\h the current iteration in the browser's event loop.\h
它會執行在瀏覽器事件迴圈的當前迭代結束前的 微任務佇列中
Making the update asynchronous can\h work, however it's very implicit\h\h
進行非同步更新可以奏效，但是它非常隱晦
and should really only be used as a last resort. It's not clear why we make this code asynchronous\h\h
只應該把它作為最後的應急措施 它無法說清楚為什麼我們要寫這段非同步程式碼
unless you understand the nuances of Angular\h change detection and the browser's event loop.\h
除非你能理解 Angular 變更檢測和瀏覽器事件迴圈中的 某些細微差異
Luckily Angular provides us with a more direct\h and explicit way to trigger change detection.\h
幸運的是，Angular 為我們提供了另一種 更直接、更明顯的方式來觸發變更檢測
We can manually trigger it by injecting the change\h detector ref in the constructor of the component.\h
我們可以透過在元件的建構函式中注入 ChangeDetectorRef 來手動觸發它
We can then use it to manually run change\h detection by calling the detect changes method.\h
然後我們就可以呼叫 detectChanges() 方法 來手動執行變更檢測
This will tell Angular to check the view and\h its children, in which case it will notice\h\h
這會要求 Angular 檢查此檢視及其子檢視 在這個例子中，這會通知它們
that our loading state has changed, giving\h us yet another way to address the error.\h
我們的 loading 狀態已經變了 這樣就給了我們另一種方式以解決本錯誤
Now an entirely different way you might encounter\h this error is when you have a method, usually a\h\h
你還可能以一種完全不同的方式遇到本錯誤 如果你有一個方法（通常是一個 getter）
getter, that doesn't return a predictable value,\h which can cause an infinite change detection loop.\h
該方法會返回不可預測的值 這樣就會導致變更檢測進入無限迴圈
Take for example this getter in our\h component that returns a random number.\h
比如，我們元件中的這個 getter 方法會返回隨機數
If we try to use this value in the\h template, Angular will get a different\h\h
如果我們試圖在範本中使用這個值 那麼每當 Angular 進行變更檢測時
value each time it's checked. The solution in this case\h\h
都會得到一個不同的值 這種情況下的解決方案是
is to make the method return a consistent\h value based on the state of the component.\h
讓該方法基於當前元件的狀態返回一個確定的值
In other words getters should be derived\h directly from the component state and\h\h
換句話說，各種 getter 都應該是從元件狀態衍生出來的
not values that change constantly\h like timestamps or random numbers.\h
而不能是那些不斷變化的值，如時間戳或隨機數
Now let's take a look at one more example, where\h we have both a parent and child component at play.\h
現在，我們來看一個更復雜的例子 這個例子中我們同時有父元件和子元件
The app component the parent contains the\h loading state just like our previous examples,\h\h
父元件 AppComponent 包含 loading 狀態 就像以前的例子中一樣
but instead of running the update from the\h parent component, we'll make it happen from\h\h
但是我們不在父元件中進行修改，而是改為
a child component with a custom event. In the item component, the child,\h\h
從子元件中使用自訂事件進行修改 在子元件 ItemComponent 中
we're using the @Output decorator to create\h a custom event along with an event emitter.\h
我們使用 @Output 裝飾器和 EventEmitter 來建立一個自訂事件
Then during ngOnInit we'll go ahead and\h emit the event with a value of true.\h
接著，在 ngOnInit 期間，我們以 true 值發出一個事件
Then back in the app component template we'll\h go ahead and declare the item component.\h
然後，回到 AppComponent 的範本中 我們繼續並宣告 ItemComponent
When it fires, we'll set\h the loading value to false.\h
當自訂事件觸發時 我們把 loading 值設定為 false
The end result is a situation where we have a\h child component updating the parent after change\h\h
最終的結果是我們有一個子元件 它在父元件的變更檢測執行完之後修改了父元件
detection has already run on the parent,\h and once again that produces the error.\h
這時候就會發生本錯誤
A potential solution in this case would be to\h move the loading state into the child component\h\h
這個例子的潛在解決方案之一 是把 loading 狀態移到子元件中
and if that's not possible you might consider\h moving this state to a shared service where it\h\h
如果這樣行不通，你可以考慮 把此狀態移到一個共享服務中
can be injected in multiple components.
而該服務可以注入到多個元件中
Let's finish up by doing a quick recap.\h
在結束之前，我們複述一下重點
The ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError\h occurs because a value in the template has been\h\h
出現 ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError 是因為範本中的某個值
updated after change detection has finished. Debug it by first finding\h\h
在變更檢測完成之後又被修改了 先找到在呼叫堆疊追蹤中給出的範本來排錯
the template in the stack trace. From there you can analyze your code to determine\h\h
從那裡，你可以分析程式碼來決定到底是
where the value is being updated and use one of\h the methods covered in this video to address it,\h\h
哪個值被修改了，並且使用本影片中涵蓋的方法之一來解決它
such as refactoring to the OnInit lifecycle\h hook, using change detector ref manually,\h\h
比如把它重構到 OnInit 鉤子中、 手動使用 ChangeDetectorRef、
making getters item potent, or making\h your updates async as a last resort.\h
讓 getter 返回確定的值 或者把修改變成非同步的，作為最後的應急手段
Refer to the Angular documentation\h for additional details and examples.
參考 Angular 官方文件，以瞭解更多詳情和範例